Nobody wants to be ordinary.
American Animals is a drama, crime, documentary film directed by Bart Layton.
Lexington, Kentucky, 2004.
Four young men attempt to execute one of the most audacious
art heists in the history of the United States.
Warren Lipka, played by Evan Peters.
Spencer Reinhard, played by Barry Keoghan.
Chas Allen, played by Blake Jenner.
Eric Borsuk, played by Jared Abrahamson.
Betty Jean 'BJ' Gooch, played by Ann Dowd.
Warren Lipka Senior, played by Gary Basaraba.
American Animals is a 2018 docudrama heist film
written and directed by Bart Layton.
Starring Evan Peters, Barry Keoghan, Blake Jenner, Jared Abrahamson, and Ann Dowd, it is an
account of the Transylvania University book heist in Lexington, Kentucky in 2004.
The film cuts between interview segments of the real-life people
involved in the heist and actors playing out the same events.
American Animals premiered at the 2018 Sundance
Film Festival on January 19, 2018.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on June
1, 2018, by The Orchard and MoviePass Ventures.
Among other awards the film won the Junior Jury
Award at The Montclair Film Festival.
It received generally favorable reviews from critics, particularly for its screenplay, acting, use of unreliable narrators, and an
unconventional storytelling structure that fused real-life characters and actors representing those characters.
The film explores themes of new york city, art
collector, library, pennsylvania, usa, artist.
The tone is emotional.